# IAN RICHARD FERGUSON, M.A.

#### COMPUTATIONAL SOCIAL SCIENTIST

703.819.0646 | IRF823@stanford.edu | GitHub.com/lanRFerguson

### PROFILE

My background in academic research has afforded me a rich computational toolbox to solve a range of technical problems. I have a demonstrated history exploring the mechanisms underlying political attitudes using nuanced and creative methodological approaches, and I am thrilled to channel these efforts to support a more progressive future.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### LAB MANAGER

#### Stanford Social Neuroscience Lab (Palo Alto, CA) 2020 - Present

- Independent research uses Machine Learning to assess relationship between changing local demographics and use of hate speech online
- Designed fully-automated neuroimaging pipeline using object-oriented Python
- Scraped and cleaned semantic data from 30+ years of congressional records, correlated with speaker ideology to identify trends in moral language usage

#### GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

# Social Cognitive and Neural Sciences Lab (New York, NY) 2018 - 2020

- Masters' thesis used Generalized estimating equations to model perceived threat of mixed-race groups in status threatened individuals
- Designed automated email reminder system for study participants

# STORE SYSTEMS INTEGRATOR

# Whole Foods Market (Richmond, VA & Brooklyn, NY) 2016-2020

- Implemented price auditing infrastructure to identify erroneous item pricing
- Automated team-specific weekly error reports using Excel macros

## SKILLS

- Python (Pandas, NumPy, SK-Learn, Flask)
- R (Tidyverse, MASS, lme4)
- **SQL** (MySQL, Postgres, SQLite, Maria DB)
- Statistics and Machine Learning fundamentals (OLS and regularized regression, significance testing, PCA and data decomposition)
- Collaboration (Git, Replit)

## EDUCATION

M.A. IN PSYCHOLOGY

New York University (2018 - 2020)

B.S. IN PSYCHOLOGY (MINOR IN BUSINESS)

Virginia Commonwealth University (2012 - 2015)